[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
So now that we've talked about several models, let's dive in into
والآن بعد أن تحدثنا حول عدة نماذج، دعونا نتعمق في
boosting more generally, and then a specific example of a boosting algorithm.
مسألة التعزيز بشكل أكثر عمومية، ثم بعد ذلك نعرض مثالًا محددًا حول خوارزمية التعزيز.
So think about a learning problem where we take some data,
فكر في إحدى مشكلات التعلم حيث نأخذ بعض البيانات
we learn a classifier which gives us some output, f(x), and
ونتعرف على أحد المصنفات والذي يعطينا بدوره بعض المخرجات والتي يرمز لها (f(x،
we use it to predict on some data so we say that y hat is a sign of f(x).
والتي نستخدمها للتنبؤ ببعض البيانات لذلك نقول أن ((y^ = sign(f(x.
So if we take some data and
لذا، إذا أخذنا بعض البيانات
we try to make a prediction, we might learn see a decision stop.
وحاولنا إجراء تنبؤ، فحينها قد نقابل أحد فروع القرارات.
So let's say you try to split on income, we look at
لذا، لنفترض أننا نحاول تقسيم الدخل، فننظر إلى
folks with income greater than 100,000, folks with income less than 100,000, and
الأشخاص ذوي الدخل الأكبر من 100000، والأشخاص ذوي الدخل الأقل من 100000،
how do we learn the actual predictions that we make?
وكيف نحصل على التنبؤات الفعلية التي نقوم بها؟
Well, we look at the rows of our data,
حسنًا، سننظر إلى صفوف البيانات لدينا،
the rows where the income was greater than 100,000, and we see that for those,
وتحديدًا الصفوف حيث يكون الدخل أكبر من 100000 ونلاحظ أنه بالنسبة لتلك الصفوف،
3 were safe loans and 1 was a risky loan, so we're going to predict y hat = safe.
فهناك ثلاثة قروض آمنة وقرض واحد به مخاطرة، لذا فسيكون التنبؤ لدينا مبن على أن y^ = آمن.
Now, if we look at incomes of less than 100,000, we'll see that we have 4 safe and
والآن، إذا نظرنا إلى الدخول التي أقل من 100000، فسنلاحظ أن لدينا أربعة قروض آمنة
3 risky, so again we predict safe, so both sides we're going to predict safe.
وثلاثة قروض بها مخاطرة، لذا فمرة أخرى نحن نجري التنبؤ على كون العملية آمنة، لذلك في كلا الجانبين سنجري التنبؤ على الأمان.
As it turns out that we do this first decision stump, seems okay, but
وكما يتضح من فرعي القرار اللذين أنشأناهما، أن الأمر يبدو حسنًا، ولكن
it doesn't seem great on the data.
الأمر ليس رائعًا بالنسبة للبيانات.
And so, decision stump wasn't enough to capture the information with
وبالتالي، فإن فروع القرار ليست كافية لتحتوي المعلومات
the limited data.
لذا، فنحن بحاجة إلى بيانات أخرى.
So a boosting will do is take that decision stump,
وما سيقوم به التعزيز هو، أخذ فرع القرار هذا،
evaluate it, look at how well it's doing in our data, and
وتقييمه والنظر إلى مدى كفاءته بالنسبة للبيانات لدينا
learn a next decision stump, a next weak classifier and then next
ثم يتعرف على فرع القرار التالي وعلى مصنف ضعيف آخر، ثم بعد ذلك
the classifier is going to focus on the data points where the first one was bad.
يقوم المصنف بالتركيز على نقاط البيانات التي فشل المصنف الأول في التركيز عليها.
So in other words, this is a very important point.
وبعبارة أخرى، هذه نقطة هامة للغاية.
In other words, we're going to look at where we're making mistakes so far and
بعبارة أخرى، سننظر إلى النقاط التي لا نزال نرتكب بها أخطاء حتى الآن
want to increase, see the proportion or the impact or
وسنقوم بزيادة نسبة أو تأثير
how much we care about the points where we've made mistakes.
أو مدى اهتمامنا بهذه النقاط التي نرتكب بها الأخطاء.
And we load in another classifier that takes care of the points that made
ثم نتعرف على مصنف آخر يهتم بتلك النقاط
mistakes and then we load another one and another one.
التي نرتكب أخطاء بها ثم نتعرف على مصنف آخر وآخر.
And eventually, as we'll see, will actually converge to a great classifier.
وكما سنرى في نهاية المطاف، فقد قمنا في الواقع بتجميع مصنف هائل.
What does it mean to learn the data points were made mistakes?
ما الذي يعنيه التعرف على نقاط البيانات التي نرتكب بها الأخطاء؟
What it means is that we're going to assign a weight,
ما يعنيه هو أننا سنقوم بتعيين الترجيح
alpha i to the positive number to every data point in our dataset.
αi وهو رقم موجب، إلى كل نقطة بيانات في مجموعة البيانات لدينا.
And that weight, when it's higher, it means that data point is more important.
ويعني هذا الترجيح عندما يكون مرتفعًا، أن نقطة البيانات تلك ذات أهمية.
So you can imagine a learning problem where we have data, not just like
لذا، يمكننا تخيل أحد مشكلات التعلم حيث يكون لدينا بيانات ليست مشابهة
we've done so far in this course, but we have data with weights associated with it.
لتلك التي تناولناها حتى الآن في هذه الدورة، ولكن لدينا بيانات مع ترجيحات مرتبطة بها.
And now we're going to learn from weighted data.
والآن سنتعلم من البيانات المرجحة.
What there is to learn from weighted data, the way to think about it is that,
ما يوجد لنتعلمه من البيانات المرجحة، طريقة التفكير في ذلك الأمر هو أن
those alpha is correspond to kind of
ترجيحات αi تلك تتوافق نوعًا ما
data points counting more than one time if its greater than one.
مع نقاط البيانات التي تحتسب أكثر من مرة واحدة إذا كانت أكبر من واحد.
So for example, if alpha i is 2,
على سبيل المثال، إذا كانت αi تساوي 2،
you can think about that data point is counting twice.
فيمكنك الاعتقاد في أن نقطة البيانات هذه تحتسب مرتين.
If the data point was half you could think about data point counting as
وإذا كانت αi تساوي النصف فيمكنك أن تعتقد أن نقطة بيانات هذه يتم احتسابها
half of a data point.
كنصف نقطة بيانات.
But everything in the learning algorithm stays exactly the same.
ولكن كل شيء في خوارزمية التعلم يظل تمامًا كما هو.
It just that instead of counting data points you count kind of weights of data
الأمر فقط أنه بدلًا من احتساب عدد نقاط البيانات فنحن نحتسب ترجيحات نقاط البيانات.
points.
.
What happens in our decision stump approach?
وهذا ما يحدث في نهج فرع القرار لدينا؟
So we had that first decision stump, it was not a great, especially for
لذا، فقد كان لدينا فرع القرار الأول، والذي لم يكن رائعًا خاصةً
folks with lower income and so we learned it's weight, which are higher for
بالنسبة للأشخاص ذوي الدخل المنخفض، لذا فقد قمنا بالتعرف على الترجيح الأعلى
the places where we've made mistakes and now we learn the new decision stump.
بالنسبة للنقاط التي نرتكب بها الأخطاء، والآن نتعرف على فرع القرار الجديد.
Let's say again we split the columns, again, written 100,000 less 100,000.
لذا، فمرة أخرى سنقوم بتقسيم الدخل إلى أكبر من 100000 وأصغر من 100000.
When we look at the classifications decisions that we make, for greater than
وعندما ننظر إلى تصنيفات القرارات التي نجريها، بالنسبة للدخل الأكبر
100,000 what we do is we sum the weight of the data points that were risky, and
من 100000، فما نفعله هو أننا نقوم بجمع ترجيح نقاط البيانات التي تشكل مخاطرة.
incomes greater than 100,000.
ولأن الدخل أكبر من 100000،
So in this case we're summing 0.5, 0.8,
فإننا في هذه الحالة سنقوم بجمع 0.5 و0.8
0.7 which adds up to 2 and then for the risky ones it's 1.2 and
و 0.7 حيث يصل مجموعهم إلى 2، ثم بعد ذلك
so we're going to make a prediction of y hat is safe.
بالنسبة للنقاط التي بها مخاطرة فالمجموع 1.2، لذا فسنقوم بإجراء التنبؤ حيث تكون y^ = آمن.
So it's the weighted sum of the data points.
لذا، فهذا هو المجموع المرجح لنقاط البيانات.
For income less than 100,000, same kind of idea.
وبالنسبة للدخل الأقل من 100000، فتطبق نفس الفكرة.
We'll go through the data points, look at the ones that were risk and
سنأخذ نقاط البيانات، ونبحث عن النقاط التي بها مخاطرة
ones that were safe and sum up the weight of those.
والنقاط الآمنة، ونقوم بحساب مجموع ترجيح هذه البيانات.
And we see the total weight of risky that 65,
وسنلاحظ أن إجمالي الترجيح بالنسبة للقروض التي بها مخاطرة هو 6.5،
the total weight of safe loans is 3, so we're going to predict what is risky.
في حين أن إجمالي الترجيح للقروض الآمنة هو 3، لذلك فنحن سنجري التنبؤ بناءً على القروض التي بها مخاطرة.
So this decision stump is now going to be a bit better.
لذا، فإن فرع القرار هذا سيكون أفضل بعض الشيء.
So we're going to combine this one with the previous one and others and
وبالتالي، سنقوم بجمع فرع القرار هذا مع الفرع السابق وغيرهما وغيرهما
others until we create this ensemble classifier.
حتى نقوم بإنشاء مصنف المجموعات هذا.
Now, this idea of learning from weighted data is not just about decision stumps.
والآن، فإن تلك الفكرة حول التعلم من البيانات المرجحة لا تتمحور فقط حول فروع القرارات.
It's the result that most machine learning algorithms accept weighted data.
فقد اتضح أن معظم خوارزميات التعلم الآلي تتقبل البيانات المرجحة.
So I'm going to show you very briefly what happens if you are doing logistical
لذا، سأوضح باختصار شديد ما يحدث إذا كنت تجري انحدارًا لوجستيًا
regression and you have weighted data.
وكانت لديك بيانات مرجحة.
So if you look at the equation on the bottom here, that's exactly the equation
إذا نظرت إلى المعادلة الموجودة بالأسفل هنا، فستجد أنها تمامًا تلك المعادلة
of logistic regressions derivative, or the update function that we do.
المتعلقة بمشتقة الانحدار اللوجستي، أو دالة التحديث التي سنقوم بها.
This is the thing that you would implement if you run a logistic regression model.
وهذا هو الأمر الذي ستقوم بتطبيقه إذا كنت تتعامل مع نموذج للانحدار اللوجستي.
Now, you say, I have this weighted data,
وتقول الآن، حسنًا، إن كل ما لدي هي تلك البيانات المرجحة،
I have to reimplement everything from scratch.
وعلي إعادة تنفيذ كل شيء من البداية.
My god, my god, my god.
يا إلهي، يا إلهي، يا إلهي.
And it turns out that it's very simple.
واتضح في النهاية أن الأمر في غاية البساطة.
You should look at the middle of the equation,
يجب عليك النظر إلى منتصف المعادلة،
we have the sum over data points over here.
حيث لدينا مجموع نقاط البيانات هنا.
And now, so we just sum our data points.
والآن، نحن نقوم ببساطة بحساب مجموع نقاط البيانات.
We're just going to weigh the contribution of each data point.
سنقوم فقط بحساب الترجيح لقيمة كل نقطة بيانات.
So we just add that weight alpha i to each term in the sum and we're done.
لذا، فنحن فقط في حاجة إلى إضافة ذلك الترجيح αi إلى كل حد من حدود المجموع، وينتهي الأمر.
We now have logistic regression for weighted data.
والآن، يصبح لدينا الانحدار اللوجستي للبيانات المرجحة.
So we showed you two examples, decision stumps and logistics regression but
لذا، فقد قمنا بعرض مثالين حول فروع القرارات والانحدار اللوجستي، ولكن
in general it's quite easy to learn with the data.
بشكل عام، فيمكن معرفة البيانات بسهولة.
So boosting can be viewed as a greedy algorithm for
لذا، فيمكن إظهار التعزيز كخوارزمية جشعة
learning an ensemble from data.
بالنسبة للتعرف على مجموعة من البيانات.
We train the first classssifier, let's say f1(x),
فنحن نقوم بتهيئة المصنف الأول من خلال البيانات، ولنفترض أنه (f1(x،
if you just have f1(x) just predict the sign of f1 to be your output of y hat.
فإذا كان لديك (f1(x فقط، فيمكنك إجراء التنبؤ على (sign(f1 لتصبح النتيجة التي ستحصل عليها من y^.
Now, then you re-weight your data
وبعد ذلك، ستقوم بإعادة حساب ترجيح البيانات لديك.
by weighting more data points where we made mistakes, where f1 makes mistakes.
وبحساب ترجيح المزيد من نقاط البيانات، فنحن نرتكب أخطاء، وحيث يرتكب المصنف f1 الأخطاء.
And now we run another classifier, f2 and
والآن سنقوم بوضع مصنف آخر وهو f2
we learn the coefficients which for these classifiers, and
وسنقوم بالتعرف على معاملات كل واحد من هذه المصنفات، ثم يأتي التنبؤ
now our prediction if we just do 2 steps of this is w hat 1, f1 + w hat 2, f2.
بالنسبة لخطوتين من كل ذلك وسيكون w^1 f1 + w^2 f2.
And the sign of that is y hat.
وحاصل ضرب ذلك في sign سيكون y^.
So that is kind of like the keep adding new classifiers,
وذلك هو نوعًا ما فكرة عمل التعزيز، حيث تستمر في إضافة مصنفات جديدة،
optimizing the weights to focus on more difficult data points and
وتقوم بتحسين الترجيحات للتركيز على
then learning the coefficients between different classifiers.
نقاط بيانات أكثر صعوبة، ثم تتعرف على المعاملات الموجودة بين المصنفات المختلفة.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]